Guide to the Marvin H. Pope Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Drafts/Unpublished Writings, Series IV
  - "Bronze-Age God Talk: The Impact of Ugaritic on Biblical Studies," draft for Dahood Memorial Lecture, n.d. (Box 21P, Folder 608)
  - "Ugaritic Words with Cognates Only in Arabic," presented at the First International Symposium on Antiquities of Palestine, 1981 (Box 21P, Folder 609)
  - "The Black Beauty of the Super Song," paper delivered at the annual SBL meeting for a special session on "Song of Songs", 1992 (Box 21P, Folder 610)
  - "YHWH and His ASRT," abstract for a paper, 1979 (Box 21P, Folder 611)
  - ""The Black Beauty of the Super Song," abstract for a paper delivered at SBL annual meeting, 1992 (Box 21P, Folder 612)
  - "Behold Now Behemoth," abstract for a paper (Box 21P, Folder 613)
  - "On Some Details in the Description of Leviathan," abstract for a paper (Box 21P, Folder 614)
  - FUMC sermon, 1978 Feb (Box 21P, Folder 615)
  - "The Brotherhood of Man," draft of a sermon (Box 21P, Folder 616-617)
  - Draft of a sermon in which Pope discusses his life experiences, the Holocaust, racism, and the Hebrew Bible (Box 21P, Folder 618)
  - "Why and How People Pray: Some Historical Perspectives," speech on behalf of the World Day of Prayer (Box 21P, Folder 619)
  - Response to P.C. Craigie on "The Religion of Ugarit: Archaeological (Non-Literary) Evidence" (Box 21P, Folder 620)
  - Half of a draft of a review and notes on "Die Personennamender Texte aus Ugarit" by Frauke Grondahl, 1967 (Box 21P, Folder 621)
  - Draft of a review of "The Goddess Anat in Ugaritic Myth" by Neal H. Walls, 1993 (Box 21P, Folder 622)
  - Draft of a review of "Ras Shamra and the Bible" by Charles F. Pfeiffer, 1962 (Box 21P, Folder 623)
  - Draft of a review of "Beatific Afterlife in Ancient Israel and in the Ancient Near East" by Spronk (Box 21P, Folder 624)
  - Drafts of a review of "Israel's Beneficent Dead" by Brian Schmidt, n.d. (Box 21P, Folder 625)
  - Pope's critique of the NRSV, n.d. (Box 21P, Folder 626)
  - Draft of a review, comments on "The Jerusalem Bible" (the French edition) (Box 22P, Folder 627)
  - Draft of a review of "The Song of Songs: A New Translation" by Ariel Bloch and Chana Bloch (Box 22P, Folder 628)
  - Draft of a review on "Song of Songs and Essenes" (Box 22P, Folder 629)
  - Critique of an article entitled "Les Chariots D'Aminadab" by R. Tournay, 1959 (Box 22P, Folder 630)
  - Draft of a review of "Canaanite Myth and Hebrew Legend" (Box 22P, Folder 631)
  - Draft of a review of "Jesus and the Riddle of the Dead Sea Scrolls" by Thiering (Box 22P, Folder 632)
  - Transliteration and interlinear translation of "The Birth of the Beautiful Gods", 1975 (Box 22P, Folder 633-634)
  - Translation of "The Birth of the Beautiful Gods" and commentary; translations by Wartman and Tuttle of "Big Mouth" (Box 22P, Folder 635)
  - Transliteration and interlinear translation of "The Birth of the Beautiful Gods" by Tuttle and Wartman (Box 22P, Folder 636)
  - Translations of "The Birth of the Beautiful Gods" by Pope, Freer and Paetzold (Box 22P, Folder 637)
  - Transliteration and interlinear translation of "The Birth of the Beautiful Gods" by Wartman (Box 22P, Folder 638)
  - Translation, notes re. "The Birth of the Beautiful Gods" (Box 22P, Folder 639-641)
  - "Baal and Anat" (Box 22P, Folder 642)
  - "Baal and Anat Cont." (Box 22P, Folder 643)
  - KTU transcript, n.d. (Box 22P, Folder 644)
  - Transliteration, translation, commentary on KTU 1.3, n.d. (Box 22P, Folder 645)
  - Transliteration, interlinear translation, commentary on KTU 1.3, n.d. (Box 22P, Folder 646)
  - translation, commentary on KTU 1.3, n.d. (Box 23P, Folder 647)
  - Translation, commentary on KTU 1.4 (Message to Kothar), n.d. (Box 23P, Folder 648)
  - Translation, commentary on KTU 1.4, n.d. (Box 23P, Folder 649-650)
  - Commentary and student work on KTU 1.4 (Box 23P, Folder 651)
  - Translation and commentary on KTU 1.4 (Box 23P, Folder 652)
  - Transliteration, interlinear translation and commentary on Text 10 (Ugaritic text) (Box 23P, Folder 653)
  - Transliteration, interlinear translation and commentary on Texts 11, 12, 13 (Ugaritic) (Box 23P, Folder 654)
  - AQHT with Renfroe's notes, n.d. (Box 23P, Folder 655-657)
  - AQHT, n.d. (Box 23P, Folder 658-660)
  - AQHT, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 661-662)
  - Translation:Athirat, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 663)
  - Translations of Ugaritic mythological poems from the Baal Cycle, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 664)
  - Translations, commentary of Ugaritic material, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 665)
  - Transliteration and interlinear translation of Keret (Box 24P, Folder 666)
  - Transliteration and translation of Keret (Box 24P, Folder 667)
  - Transliteration, translation of Miscellaneous Ugaritic texts, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 668)
  - "Dining Invitations in Hebrew and Ugaritic Poetry"; "Cutting Deals"; "Social Justice" (how source of this ideal is older than the Hebrew Bible) (Box 24P, Folder 669)
  - "The name Israel at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 670)
  - "Darkness and Eternity," Hebrew Bible parallels (Box 24P, Folder 671)
  - "Ugaritic Clears Up Some Garbled Passages in Holy Writ", n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 672)
  - Draft re. relevance of Ugaritic poetry to the understanding of biblical poetry (Box 24P, Folder 673)
  - "Wine in the Hebrew Bible and Ugaritic Texts" (Box 24P, Folder 674)
  - Draft re. parallels between Ugaritic and biblical poetry (Box 24P, Folder 675)
  - "Intro; About Israel" re. the impact of Ugaritic texts on Biblical Studies, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 676)
  - Draft re. biblical poetry, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 677)
  - "Numerical Dicta in Ugaritic and Biblical Poetry" (Box 24P, Folder 678)
  - Draft re. biblical poetry entitled "Strength and Song" (Box 24P, Folder 679)
  - Draft re. common literary tradition underlying Ugaritic and biblical poesy (Box 24P, Folder 680)
  - "Janus Parallelism" re. poetry, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 681)
  - "Biblical Parallels", n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 682)
  - "Ugaritic and Emendation of Biblical Text"; "Day One"; "Soul"; "Hell Free?: Biblical Parallel" (Box 24P, Folder 683)
  - "Music and Poetry" re. Ugarit and the Hebrew Bible (Box 24P, Folder 684)
  - "Introduction"; prospectus for a vol. intended for the Anchor Bible Reference Library re. Ugarit and The Bible (Box 24P, Folder 685)
  - "Music at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 686)
  - Draft of a letter to Mike re. proposed volume on Ugarit and the Bible for the Anchor Bible Reference Library, 1990s (Box 24P, Folder 687)
  - "Introduction" re. mythological texts in Ugaritic literature, n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 688)
  - "Ugaritic Words", n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 689)
  - Draft re. colometry and Ugaritic poetic texts (Box 24P, Folder 690)
  - "Introduction--Personal Memories" re. Ugarit and the need to popularize its discovery; "Introduction--The Impact of Ugaritic on Biblical Studies" (Box 24P, Folder 691)
  - "The Ugaritic Language", n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 692)
  - "Affinities of Ugaritic with the Bible", n.d. (Box 24P, Folder 693)
  - "Popescript": tips on analyzing Ugaritic texts, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 694)
  - "Circumcision at Ugarit?", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 695)
  - Draft re. Ugaritic texts and etymology (Box 25P, Folder 696)
  - "Myths and Legends of Ugarit": a proposal/description of Pope's planned book of annotated translations of Ugaritic texts (Box 25P, Folder 697)
  - Draft re. Ugaritic mythological poetry project; "Origin of the Word Bible"; statement of purpose, etc., n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 698)
  - "Introduction"; "Ugaritic and Biblical Studies," part of Pope's project on Ugaritic mythological poems (Box 25P, Folder 699)
  - Miscellaneous notes re. Ugaritic texts, draft of manuscript, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 700)
  - Draft re. Mot, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 701)
  - "Bon Appetit," re. Mot and death (Box 25P, Folder 702)
  - "Nikkal", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 703)
  - "Kothar", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 704)
  - Draft re. Keret; "Inverse Primogeniture"; "The Channel", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 705)
  - "The KRT Epic", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 706)
  - "I Know That Mighty Baal Lives", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 707)
  - "Mighty Baal and Job's Redeemer" (Box 25P, Folder 708)
  - Draft re. Baal-Anat poem, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 709)
  - "Peace on Earth" re. Baal and Anat (Box 25P, Folder 710)
  - "Hate at Ugarit--Baal", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 711)
  - Transcription, translation and commentary on "The Keret Epic" (Box 25P, Folder 712)
  - Draft re. Baal, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 713)
  - Draft re. Baal Cycle, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 714)
  - "Chapter VI: Reflections of the Baal-Mot Cycle in the Old Testament", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 715)
  - drafts on aspects of Baal, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 716)
  - draft on "ly"; "Aliyn"; "Baal's Paternity", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 717)
  - "EUP," draft re. El, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 718)
  - "Eternal Dominion," draft re. El (Box 25P, Folder 719)
  - "On the Evolution of El," incomplete draft, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 720)
  - "The Status of El at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 721)
  - "The Status of El at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 722)
  - "The Status of El at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 723)
  - "The Status of El in the Ugaritic Texts," abstract, n.d. (Box 25P, Folder 724)
  - Pages from a notebook containing a draft of "The Major Deities of Ugarit", n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 725)
  - "The Gods and Myths of Ancient Ugarit" (Box 26P, Folder 726)
  - "The Divine Family and the Gods of the Heathen," re. Ugaritic mythological poems (Box 26P, Folder 727)
  - "God's Seventy Children and Their Heritage" (Box 26P, Folder 728)
  - "God's Seventy Children and the Heathen" (Box 26P, Folder 729)
  - "God's Seventy Children and the Heathen," typed draft (Box 26P, Folder 730)
  - "God's Family," original draft, n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 731)
  - "God's Family", n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 732)
  - "God's Family", n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 733)
  - "Athirat's Children and the Gods of the Nations" (Box 26P, Folder 734)
  - "Athirat's Children and the Gods of the Nations" (Box 26P, Folder 735)
  - "God's Wife", n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 736)
  - "Anat's Blood Bath: Grapes of Wrath"; 2 drafts on the same subject, n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 737)
  - Draft re. Anat, her relationship to the Indian goddess Kali, etc. (Box 26P, Folder 738)
  - "The Goddess Anat and Kali" (Box 26P, Folder 739)
  - "Who Drank Whom and Why?" draft in response to the discovery that the 1st word of KTU 1.96 was different from what was previously thought (Box 26P, Folder 740)
  - "Evil Eye or Voracious Virgin?"; several drafts, n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 741)
  - "Cannibalism Among the Gods", n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 742)
  - "Discovery of Ugarit", n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 743-744)
  - Introduction to "Discovery of Ugaritic Texts", n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 745-747)
  - Draft re. discovery of Ugarit and Ugaritic writings (Box 26P, Folder 748)
  - "Ugarit Unearthed", n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 749)
  - "Ugarit," re. site, tablets, etc., n.d. (Box 26P, Folder 750)
  - Draft re. the history and geography of Ugarit (Box 26P, Folder 751-752)
  - "The Devil (or Demon Rum) at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 753)
  - Draft re. angels at Ugarit, n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 754)
  - "Angels in the Ugaritic Myths"; "The Evolution of Angels"; "Angels at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 755)
  - "Angels" re. superhuman beings, God and lesser deities (Box 27P, Folder 756)
  - "Angels, Slaves, Powers of the Dead" Part II, n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 757)
  - "Angels", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 758)
  - "Angels in the Bible"; "Angels as Divine Slaves"; "Angels at Ugarit and in the Bible" (Box 27P, Folder 759)
  - Draft re. supernatural spirits and powers (Box 27P, Folder 760)
  - "Soul", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 761)
  - Gods/goddesses at Ugarit, n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 762-766)
  - Materials for "A Divine Banquet at Ugarit", 1972 (Box 27P, Folder 767-770)
  - "Sacrifices at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 771)
  - "The Cult of the Dead at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 772)
  - "Strong as Death", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 773)
  - "Mourning Rites: Going to Hell", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 774)
  - Draft re. unction at Ugarit and in the Bible (Box 27P, Folder 775)
  - "Firstborn and Lastborn" (Box 27P, Folder 776)
  - "Ultimogeniture", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 777)
  - ""Ten as a Critical Mass in Social, Religious Activity" re. Hebrew Bible and Ugarit (Box 27P, Folder 778)
  - "Good News (Gospel) at Ugarit", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 779)
  - "Ugaritic Words with Cognates Only in Arabic", 1986 (Box 27P, Folder 780)
  - "The MRZH at Ugarit and Elsewhere" (Box 27P, Folder 781)
  - "Le MRZH a Ougarit et ailleurs", n.d. (Box 27P, Folder 782)
  - bk, n.d. (Box 28P, Folder 783)
  - "Grammatical Items: Vocative L and Enclitic-M" (Box 28P, Folder 784)
  - Ugaritic Enclitic M, n.d. (Box 28P, Folder 785-787)
  - "Simple Copulative, Conjunctive Use of W"; "The Particle P", n.d. (Box 28P, Folder 788)
  - "Ugaritic W, P, L + M", n.d. (Box 28P, Folder 789)
  - "Etymology of the word 'dhimmi' ", n.d. (Box 28P, Folder 790)
  - "On the Verb nbd in Ugaritic" re: sexual relation between Ba'al and Anat" (Box 28P, Folder 791)
  - Del Olmo Lete introduction, n.d. (Box 28P, Folder 792-795)
- Course-related Material, 1966-1989, n.d.; Series V
  - Quiz on Egypt for Religion S309; lecture notes, n.d. (Box 28P, Folder 796)
  - Notes related to the lecture "Some Notes on Terminology in the Discussion of Jewish Identity", 1966 (Box 28P, Folder 797)
  - Syllabus for Religion 102a: English Exegesis, "The Late Wisdom Tradition in Israel (Job)", 1968-1969 (Box 28P, Folder 798)
  - Miscellaneous student papers, 1970-1989 (Box 28P, Folder 799)
  - Materials for "A Divine Banquet at Ugarit", 1972 (Box 29P, Folder 800)
  - Religious Studies 19a: examination on Job, 1974 Dec (Box 29P, Folder 801)
  - Religious Studies 19a: examination on Job, 1974 Dec (Box 29P, Folder 802)
  - Religious Studies 19b: examination on Song of Songs, 1975 May (Box 29P, Folder 803)
  - Syllabi: Near East 19a/229a and Near East 144b/544b, 1979 (Box 29P, Folder 804)
  - Lecture notes on Job: "Prosody"; "Literary Integrity/Unity"; "Literary Form", 1979 (Box 29P, Folder 805)
  - Lecture notes on Job, 1979 (Box 29P, Folder 806)
  - Lecture notes on Job: "Language"; "The Hebrew Language"; "Israel/Jew", and notes on text itself, 1979 (Box 29P, Folder 807)
  - Lecture notes on Job: "Date"; "Content/Structure"; "Authorship"; "Canon", 1979 (Box 29P, Folder 808)
  - Lecture notes on Job, 1979 (Box 29P, Folder 809)
  - Student papers from Pope's Ugaritic seminars, 1980s (Box 29P, Folder 810)
  - Course offering of the NELC department, 1980-1981 (Box 29P, Folder 811)
  - Class list for undergraduate course entitled "Holy Humor", 1982 (Box 29P, Folder 812)
  - Students paper from Ugaritic seminar, 1982 (Box 29P, Folder 813)
  - Near East 148a/548a: introductory lecture, n.d. (Box 29P, Folder 814)
  - Syllabus: Yale Divinity School Rel. 102a: English Exegesis, n.d. (Box 29P, Folder 815)
  - Notes/materials on the subject of humor and holy humor (Box 29P, Folder 816)
  - "Holy Humor" course: course description, list of lecture topics, n.d. (Box 29P, Folder 817)
  - "Holy Humor" course: lecture notes, bibliography, collected jokes, n.d. (Box 29P, Folder 818)
  - History of the Ancient Near East: lecture notes, n.d. (Box 29P, Folder 819-820)
  - Background notes on Job re. various themes (Box 29P, Folder 821)
  - Lecture notes re. anti-semitism, city of Ugarit, n.d. (Box 29P, Folder 822)
  - Syllabi from other professors in NELC Dept., n.d. (Box 29P, Folder 823)
  - Descriptions of courses taught by Marianne Luijken and her c.v. (Box 29P, Folder 824)
  - Miscellaneous student papers, n.d. (Box 30P, Folder 825)
  - Miscellaneous course syllabi, n.d. (Box 30P, Folder 826)
- Collected Material, 1953-1995, n.d.; Series VI
  - Newspaper clipping re: 26th Intl. Conference of Orientalists; The Hindustan Times, 1964 Jan (Box 30P, Folder 827)
  - Miscellaneous material re. Anchor Bible Mitchell Dahood prize, n.d. (Box 30P, Folder 828)
  - Publication of the annual meeting of the American Academy of Religion Society of Biblical Literature, 1996 (Box 30P, Folder 829)
  - Collected material re. AAR and A.S.S.R., various dates (Box 30P, Folder 830)
  - ASOR newsletter and correspondence, 1995 spring (Box 30P, Folder 831)
  - Fulbright Assn. newsletter; info. re. The Second International Congress of Yemenite Jewish Studies; National Humanities Center (Box 30P, Folder 832)
  - Program from the N. Carolina Parents and Teachers Annual Convention, 1961-1962 (Box 30P, Folder 833)
  - Special Education Bulletin Board vol. #3, issue 1, 1964 Oct (Box 30P, Folder 834)
  - Collected material re. dog symbolism, various dates (Box 30P, Folder 835)
  - Photographs of depictions of dogs with gods, various dates (Box 30P, Folder 836)
  - Article sent to Pope by John W. Cook on the subject of dogs; includes Pope's notes in the margins (Box 30P, Folder 837)
  - Collected material re. N. Semitic Epigraphy, n.d. (Box 30P, Folder 838)
  - Collected material re. epigraphy, n.d. (Box 30P, Folder 839)
  - Collected material/notes re. "The Great Goddess", n.d. (Box 30P, Folder 840-843)
  - Collected material/notes re. "The Great Goddess", n.d (Box 31P, Folder 844-851)
  - Photo of ancient manuscripts, misc., n.d. (Box 31P, Folder 852)
  - Article on biblical and Tamil poetry by Peter C. Craigie (Box 31P, Folder 853)
  - Genesis apocryphon col. XX "Sarah's Beauty", n.d. (Box 31P, Folder 854)
  - Newspaper clippings re. Akkadians, n.d. (Box 31P, Folder 855)
  - Flyers re. Pope's lecture on "The Love-Death Connection in Solomonic Super Song" presented at the College de France, 1990 (Box 31P, Folder 856)
  - Abstracts of papers presented at the SBL Song of Songs session, 1992 (Box 31P, Folder 857)
  - paper by Martin Samuel Cohen, entitled "The Song of Songs and the Shi'ur Qomah," presented at the SBL Song of Songs session, 1992 (Box 31P, Folder 858)
  - "The Song of Solomon Illustrated for Our Literalist Friends" (Box 31P, Folder 859-860)
  - Publicity for Pope's Anchor Bible commentary on Songs of Songs, n.d. (Box 31P, Folder 861)
  - Newsclippings re. Pope's Anchor Bible Job commentary, 1965-1966 (Box 31P, Folder 862-863)
  - "The Elihu Speeches in The Book of Job" by David Noel Freedman, 1967 May (Box 31P, Folder 864)
  - Walter Ludwig Michel's thesis on "The Ugaritic Texts and The Mythological Expression in The Book of Job" (Box 31P, Folder 865)
  - "The Atlantic," including an article entitled "Translating the Bible: An Endless Task.", 1985 Feb (Box 31P, Folder 866)
  - Collected material re. NRSV, 1990 May (Box 31P, Folder 867)
  - "The Bible: Translators and Translations" in "The Reformed Review", 1990 (Box 31P, Folder 868)
  - Newspaper clippings re. the Dead Sea Scrolls, 1953-1992 (Box 31P, Folder 869)
  - "The Scrolls from the Dead Sea" in "The New Yorker", 1955 May (Box 32P, Folder 870)
  - Article on the Dead Sea Scrolls in "Time", 1957 April (Box 32P, Folder 871)
  - Dead Sea Scrolls collected material: photographs of His Eminence Mar Athanasius Y. Samuel; unidentified photograph, n.d. (Box 32P, Folder 872)
  - Collected material re. Pope's "Brotherhood of Man" sermon, 1990s (Box 32P, Folder 873)
  - Collected material re. "Brotherhood of Man" sermon: newspaper clippings, Time magazine; articles, etc., 1989-1991 (Box 32P, Folder 874)
  - Photocopy of the Mishnah Sanhedrin 4:5 in English and Hebrew (Box 32P, Folder 875)
  - "Issues: Journal of Jewish Identity", 1967-1968 (Box 32P, Folder 876)
  - Materials re. the Jewish Cemetery of Worms, n.d. (Box 32P, Folder 877)
  - "Life" magazine spread on Islam, 1955 May (Box 32P, Folder 878)
  - Collected material re. Palestinians/Islam, n.d. (Box 32P, Folder 879)
  - "The United Presbyterian", 1953 Nov-Dec (Box 32P, Folder 880)
  - Index of Christian Art: Princeton University (Box 32P, Folder 881)
  - Collected material re. The Open Orthodox University, n.d. (Box 32P, Folder 882)
  - "Search for Sodom and Gomorrah" by Ralph E. Baney; see correps. with W.F. Albright re. Baney (Box 32P, Folder 883)
  - Newsletter for Ugaritic Studies, 1973-1986 (Box 32P, Folder 884-886)
  - Collected material related to a Manchester symposium: "Ugaritic Passages"; "Intro. to Discourse in Ugaritic and Hebrew", 1992 (Box 32P, Folder 887)
  - Collected material related to symposium on Ugaritic and the Bible: info., list of participants' addresses (Box 32P, Folder 888)
  - Miscellaneous collected material re. KTU 1.96: "Anat and the Evil Eye" by W. J. Jobling; "The Loves of Baal and Anath I"; "Who Ate and Drank Whom (KTU 1.96), paper proposal for SBL Ugaritic Section (Box 32P, Folder 889)
  - Collected material: drawings/photographs of Ugaritic figures, Ugaritic texts collected for a booket entitled "Ugaritic ABG's", n.d. (Box 32P, Folder 890)
  - Article on Ugarit in "Bible et Terre Sainte", 1964 (Box 32P, Folder 891)
  - "The Deities of Ras Shamra: Old Testament Parallels", n.d. (Box 32P, Folder 892)
  - Prints of different deities from Ugarit and other ancient places (Box 33P, Folder 893)
  - Ugaritic collected material: photocopies, prints of Ugaritic artwork, tablets, etc., n.d. (Box 33P, Folder 894)
  - Prints of Ugaritic stelae and statues (Box 33P, Folder 895)
  - Pope's notes re. Ugaritic stelae and statues, etc. (Box 33P, Folder 896)
  - Ugaritic collected material: articles, drawings, notes, misc., n.d. (Box 33P, Folder 897)
  - Ugaritic collected material re. Baal, n.d. (Box 33P, Folder 898)
- Personal/Memorabilia, 1916-1998; Series VII
  - Marvin Pope's birth certificate, original and copies, 1916 June (Box 33P, Folder 899)
  - Honorable discharge form from the 20th Weather Sq., 1945 Aug (Box 33P, Folder 900)
  - "Last Will and Testament of Helen T. Pope", 1966 June (Box 33P, Folder 901)
  - "Last Will and Testament of Marvin H. Pope Sr.", plus addendum, 1966 June, 1981 (Box 33P, Folder 902)
  - Material re. Helen T. Pope: birth certificate, death certificate, copies of her obituary, 1920, 1979 (Box 33P, Folder 903)
  - Personal correspondence with a former student re. loan, 1981-1993 (Box 33P, Folder 904)
  - "Last Will and Testament of Marvin H. Pope", 1982 (Box 33P, Folder 905)
  - Certificate of marriage between Marvin Pope and Ingrid Brostrom Bloomquist, 1985 (Box 33P, Folder 906)
  - Antenuptial agreement between Marvin Pope and Ingrid Brostrom Bloomquist, 1986 (Box 33P, Folder 907)
  - Minute read by Dean Thomson re. Pope's retirement from Yale, 1986 May (Box 33P, Folder 908)
  - Retirement memorabilia, 1986 (Box 33P, Folder 909)
  - "Love and Death in the Ancient Near East: Essays in Honor of Marvin H. Pope", 1987 (Box 33P, Folder 910)
  - Hardcover copy of "Love and Death in the Ancient Near East: Essays in Honor of Marvin H. Pope", 1986 (Box 33P, Folder 911)
  - "Last Will and Testament of Marvin H. Pope, Sr." and related correspondence, 1987 (Box 33P, Folder 912)
  - "Living Will of Marvin H. Pope", 1991 (Box 33P, Folder 913)
  - The Marquis Who's Who in the World certificate, 1991-1992 (Box 33P, Folder 914)
  - Letter re. power of attorney, 1992 (Box 33P, Folder 915)
  - Marvin H. Pope's obituaries; program from memorial service at Yale Divinity School, 1997 (Box 33P, Folder 916A)
  - "A Potpourri of Popery: Marginalia from the Life and Notes of Marvin H. Pope" by Mark Smith, includes biographical information, 1998 (Box 33P, Folder 916)
  - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Assoc. College Retirement Equities Fund, 1985-1996 (Box 33P, Folder 917)
  - Information re. the 15th Weather Squadron Association, various dates (Box 33P, Folder 918)
  - Publication: "Air Weather Service: Our Weather", 1937-1987 (Box 33P, Folder 919)
  - Photocopies of photographs of Marvin H. Pope and Ingrid Brostrom Bloomquist (Box 33P, Folder 920)
  - Newspaper clipping re. Marvin H. Pope and Ingrid Brostrom Bloomquist (Box 33P, Folder 921)
  - Pamphlets/Re: The Marvin H. Pope Scholarship Fund and Prize in Biblical Hebrew (Box 33P, Folder 922)